Richard Adekponya

Tsotso Kotei Street, Accra, Greater Accra Region | +233246843271 richrichie582@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/richard-adekponya-319b18178/

Summary

Richard kabu Adekponya is a Software Engineer having speciality in back end development. Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for restful web services projects. Well-versed in programming languages including Java, OOP, and MySQL. and a problem solver, this is the main motive for pursuing a software engineer career path. The combination of creativity and skill required to make something beautiful from code continues to repeatedly ignite my love for the beautiful art of programming.

Experience

IT CONSORTIUM, GHANA, LEGON | GREATER ACCRA, ACCRA BACKEND DEVELOPER | 05/2020 - Present

- Specialize in system integrations, build scalable restful APIs and develop USSD Applications
- Work in team to develop robust application used by over a million users
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks specifically back-end server code role
- Self deploy tested codes to pass User Acceptance Stage through to production.
- Work with the infrastructure team of effective code deployment on Amazon Web Services.
- Integrations with Bank and corporate firms for most payment systems API using spring boot framework
- Managed Applications on Linux environments and ensure all application dependencies are satisfied.

UNIVERSITY OF GHANA COMPUTER ENGINEERING DEPARTMENT GREATER ACCRA, ACCRA RESEARCH AND TEACHING ASSISTANCE | 09/2019- 08/2020

• Worked as a Teaching Assistance in the department of Computer Engineering for a list of lecturers to aid students' understanding in courses that seem confusing after being taught by the lecturer.

JAVA DEVELOPERS | GREATER ACCRA, ACCRA | 05/2019 - 08/2019

• Worked in a team to accomplish a real estate project. My position basically was to create a scalable backend restful API service with server side interaction

Skills

JAVA AWS MYSQL MICROSERVICES SPRINGBOOT GIT REDIS RABBITMQ BATCH SYSTEM LINUX HTML CSS JAVASCRIPT REACT

Education

UNIVERSITY OF GHANA | LEGON, GREATER ACCRA BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER ENGINEERING | 05/2019 Total GPA of 3.3/4.0(Second Class Upper Honors)

Projects

Employee Management System— Personal Project in progress

Used tools and frameworks such as spring boot and react in developing a fully fledged basic functional web application inculcating the basic principles and algorithms in development.

Payment Processing API

With the help of the spring boot framework I developed an API for payment processing to aid financial institutions and fintechs successfully integrate with our payment processing gateways.

Multiple Ussd Applications

Developed multiple spring boot applications for different financial institutions to aid banking on a go for traditional users who do not have alternate mobile applications for processing transactions.